Qunliang Xing · Computer Vision and Multimedia

RYANXINGQL.GITHUB.IO · RYANXINGQL@GMAIL.COM · October, 2024

Education

09.2019 - Present Doctor of Philosophy Beihang University with an Honors degree

Advisor | Professor Mai Xu

Major | Communication and Information Systems

09.2015 - 07.2019Bachelor of Engineering Beihang University with an Honors degree

Major | Communication and Information Systems

Selected Publications

 $\begin{array}{c} {\rm IEEE/CVF} \ {\rm CVPR} \\ 2024 \end{array}$

Enhancing Quality of Compressed Images by Mitigating Enhancement Bias Towards Compression Domain

Q. Xing, M. Xu, S. Li, X. Deng, M. Zheng, H. Liu, Y. Chen

Identified and mitigated enhancement bias, thereby improving the quality of enhanced compressed images.

 $\begin{array}{c} \text{IEEE TPAMI} \\ 2023 \end{array}$

DAQE: Enhancing the Quality of Compressed Images by Exploiting the Inherent Characteristic of Defocus

Q. Xing, M. Xu, X. Deng, Y. Guo

Proposed an intra-image divide-and-conquer enhancement strategy based on defocus, which indicates region-wise compression quality.

IEEE/CVF CVPRW 2022

Progressive Training of a Two-stage Framework for Video Restoration

Q. Xing*, M. Zheng*, M. Qiao*, M. Xu, L. Jiang, H. Liu, Y. Chen

NTIRE winning solution: Integrated a series of contributions on dataset construction, inference architecture design, and training strategy optimization.

ECCV 2020 Early Exit or Not: Resource-efficient Blind Quality Enhancement for Compressed Images

Q. Xing, M. Xu, T. Li, Z. Guan

Proposed a multi-level early-exit enhancement strategy based on real-time quality assessment for the blind quality enhancement challenge.

IEEE TPAMI 2019

MFQE 2.0: A New Approach for Multi-frame Quality Enhancement on Compressed Video

Q. Xing, Z. Guan, M. Xu, R. Yang, T. Liu, Z. Wang

Enhanced low-quality frames using key frames in hierarchical encoding, effectively improving compressed video quality and mitigating quality fluctuations.

Community Service

02.2021 - Present

Reviewer

TIP ('21-), TMM ('21-), TCSVT ('22-), JAS ('22-) CVPR ('25, '24), AAAI ('25), ICME ('21)

Qunliang Xing · Computer Vision and Multimedia

RYANXINGQL.GITHUB.IO · RYANXINGQL@GMAIL.COM · October, 2024

Work Experience

12.2021 - 12.2023 Research Intern	Alibaba Tao Technology Acted as the main contributor in the NTIRE CVPR 2022 Video Quality Enhancement Challenge, responsible for dataset construction, inference architecture design, and training strategy optimization. The proposed solution won the competition, competing against teams from ETH, CUHK's XPixel lab, Tencent's GY-Lab, and others.
07.2021 - 09.2021 Research Intern	Tencent Rhino-bird Open-source Training Program Selected as one of the 127 participants out of more than 1800 candidates; replicated
	recent work based on the high-performance graph computing platform Angel.
12.2018 - 12.2019	Huawei 2012 Lab
Research Intern	Served as the main contributor for multi-frame decoding quality optimization on
	Huawei's proprietary encoder HW.265; achieved over a 10% BD-BR gain on a real
	business dataset covering a large volume of UGC and live game streaming videos.

Honors and Awards

2023	China National Scholarship
	Highest national award available to graduate students.
2023	Beihang Academic Excellence Foundation for Ph.D. Candidates Ranked 1st/96 in the college.
2022	Glarun Scholarship by the 14TH Research Institute, CETC Among four awardees from 96 college students.
2022	Winner of the CVPR NTIRE challenge on Super-Resolution and Quality Enhancement of Compressed Video Ranked 1st/8 in the final.
2019	Beihang Excellent Graduate Top 20% in the university.
2015/18/21/22	Beihang Outstanding/Merit Student Top 5% in the university.
2014	Shenzhen Merit Student Sole awardee in the school.

Biography

Qunliang Xing is currently a Ph.D. student at Beihang University advised by Professor Mai Xu. He obtained his BEng and Honors degrees at Beihang University in 2019.

His research interests include Computer Vision and Multimedia. He has published several papers in top journals and conferences such as TPAMI and CVPR, including a top 1% highly cited paper recognized by the Essential Science Indicators (ESI). His papers have received over 500 citations. He has won two NTIRE championships. His open-source projects have received more than 700 stars. He was selected for the Tencent Rhino-bird Open-source Training Program. He is awarded the OpenMMLab Active Contributor. He serves as a reviewer for CVPR, TIP, TMM, and others.

He also excels in sports, having won second place in the Beihang 100m final and the Beihang soccer championship as the school team captain twice.